Episode 21
第 21 集
How foolish I am...
我是多么愚蠢啊...
Because I lost to you before.
因为我之前就输给了你。
You are proud and selfish.
你很骄傲又自私。
You would rather suffer than lose your dignity.
你 宁愿受苦，也不愿失去尊严。
You're always blaming others...
你总是指责别人...
When there is a problem.
当出现问题时。
Is Zhong Yeran the only person in this vast world?
这浩瀚的世界，就只有钟夜然一个人吗？
Can't you live without that person?
没有那个人你就活不下去吗？
You live in a small world!
你生活在一个小世界里！
Who are you to criticize me?
你是谁，敢批评我？
Aren't you the same?
你不也一样吗？
It's not that you can't live without that person .
并不是说没有那个人你就活不下去 。
I want to know how he feels.
我想知道他的感受如何。
That day on the cliff...
那天在悬崖上...
I am waiting for him to choose.
我在等他选择。
If that person chooses you, I'll jump off a cliff...
如果那个人选择了你， 我就跳崖……
And stop talking crazy about him.
别再疯狂地谈论他了。
- If he... - What good is a mouth?
- 如果他... - 一张嘴有什么用？
How about asking him?
问问他怎么样？
If you want to break up, break up.
如果你想分手，就分手吧。
Why all the fuss?
为什么这么大惊小怪？
Of course, I can't bear to break up with that person...
当然，我不忍心和那个人分手……
But you don't want to admit it.
但你不愿意承认。
Didn't you lure me here to hear this?
你不是为了听这个才引诱我来这里的吗？
The more tragic my story, the happier you are.
我的故事越悲惨， 你就越幸福。
I don't care about your tragedy.
我不在乎你的悲剧。
You are here...
你在这里...
Because of your plan...
因为你的计划...
Jong-ye is suing...
钟业正在起诉...
It caused my brother's death.
它 导致了我兄弟的死亡。
me...
我...
I have no intention of harming any of you.
我无意伤害你们任何人。
- There's just someone else... - I know.
- 还有其他人... - 我知道。
If it weren't for your evil plan...
如果不是你的邪恶计划......
No one will get a chance.
没有人会有机会。
So, you have to take responsibility...
所以，你必须承担起责任……
Because of my brother's death.
因为我哥哥的死。
Now you know how I feel, right?
现在你知道我的感受了吧？
Now you mourn for your brother.
现在 你正在为你的兄弟哀悼。
While my assistant Linglong died...
当我的助手 玲珑去世时……
I'm sad too...
我也很难过...
So I can't eat or sleep.
所以我吃不下，睡不着。
He is like a member of my family.
他就像我家庭的一员。
Hua Shen caused his death.
华神害死了他。
So blood debt is paid with blood.
所以血债是要用血来偿还的。
We are tied now.
我们现在绑在一起了。
I won't bother the Hua Family from now on.
以后我不会打扰华家了。
No, we are not tied.
不，我们没有被束缚。
Because of your trick, I fell off a cliff.
因为你的诡计，我跌下了悬崖。
I almost died.
我差点死了。
I surveyed the mountain.
我勘察了这座山。
There's a lake below...
下面有一个湖...
Thick vines grow along the cliffs.
悬崖边生长着粗壮的藤蔓。
You won't die.
你不会死的。
In the end, I didn't even think about it...
最后我连想都没想...
I want to give you measles.
我想给你传染麻疹。
I'm just...
我只是...
Build your own golden bridge.
建造你自己的金桥。
so?
所以？
In the end , I fell off the cliff.
最后 ，我跌下了悬崖。
So what do you want?
所以你想要什么？
Take my life?
夺走我的生命？
Your life is worthless.
你的生命毫无价值。
I'd like to know the mastermind behind it...
我想知道背后的主谋
Another group.
另一组。
How do you find out who they are?
你如何知道他们是谁？
If you don't know, research it.
如果你不知道，就研究一下。
Aren't you always persistent?
你不是一直都很执着吗？
What happened to your confidence?
你的自信怎么了？
You need to fix the problem you caused .
您需要解决您造成的问题 。
listen.
听。
Wu Shuomo couldn't get food.
吴硕墨拿不到饭吃。
So you'd better hurry...
所以你最好快点...
Before I starve to death.
在我饿死之前。
It is certain that you will let Master Wu Young die...
肯定会让无公大师死的……
In your custody?
在你的监护下吗？
Who said it was Master Wooyoung?
谁说是吴洋大师？
The person I caught...
我抓到的那个人...
He is a slave who ran away from our home.
他是一个从我们家逃出来的奴隶。
- Have you... - Have you decided?
- 你... - 你决定了吗？
Come back after you decide. I won't let you go.
决定之后再回来。 我不会让你走的。
Tuan.
团。
why? Why are you embarrassed?
为什么？ 你为什么尴尬？
Tuan.
团。
New information has been discovered...
发现了新的信息...
About the banquet murder.
关于宴会凶杀案。
How dare you? They are so brave!
你怎么敢？ 他们是如此勇敢！
Sir, we cannot deal with criminals...
先生，我们 不能对付罪犯……
Based on information provided by spies .
根据间谍提供的信息 。
Otherwise it will show...
不然会显示...
Zhong Family spies are all over the city.
钟家的探子 遍布全城。
Why can't I see it?
为什么我看不到？
Something happened recently...
最近发生了一些事...
It happened inside and outside the imperial castle.
事情发生在皇城内外。
The same goes for the south.
南方也是如此。
But they haven't acted yet.
但他们还没有行动。
Meanwhile, Sakibaki of the crab family...
与此同时，螃蟹一族的崎爆……
Still not giving up.
仍然没有放弃。
There is danger there ...
那里有危险 ……
You must refrain from rash actions
你必须避免鲁莽的行动 ......
It can lower the morale of our soldiers .
它会降低我们士兵的士气 。
Of course you know!
你当然知道！
This is why...
这就是为什么...
They are so arrogant!
他们太嚣张了！
go away.
离开。
All right.
好的。
You're really brave...
你真的很勇敢...
This guy!
这家伙！
I will go to bed soon.
我很快就去睡觉了。
The uninvited guest has already left.
不速之客 已经离开了。
You don't have to manage this part anymore.
您不必再管理这部分了。
I want to kill someone.
我想杀人。
I may be of help.
我可能会有所帮助。
I didn't ask who that person was.
我没有问那个人是谁。
What if he was a big guy?
如果他是个大人物呢？
If you want to kill someone, I'll help you.
如果你想杀人， 我会帮你。
You are still a child.
你还是个孩子。
Don't talk about killing .
别谈杀人 。
I am no longer a boy.
我不再是一个男孩了。
I killed people.
我杀了人。
i know.
我知道。
I do not know.
我不知道。
OK. I don't know, do you understand?
好的。 不知道你明白吗？
As you get older...
随着年龄的增长...
You prefer arguing with me.
你更喜欢和我争论。
Go to bed early.
早点睡。
Your people are still here.
你的人还在这里。
I don't think it's hard to figure out.
我认为这并不难弄清楚。
Okay, I'll look into it further...
好的，我会进一步研究一下...
But we can't stand still...
但我们不能坐以待毙……
While you are under arrest.
当你被捕时。
I know Hua Qian.
我认识华谦。
He won't hurt you.
他不会伤害你。
But if you postpone it...
但如果推迟的话...
I do not guarantee that Hua Qian will not harm her .
我不保证花千月不会伤害她 。
Your concubine, I need your advice.
你的妾， 我需要你的建议。
Where do we want to start our investigation?
我们要从哪里开始调查？
Look for traitors in your group .
寻找你的团队中的叛徒 。
Who is he?
他是谁？
Don't you want to show yourself?
你不想展现自己吗？
If I don't say anything...
如果我什么都不说的话...
How long are you planning on hiding it?
你打算隐藏多久？
Until you voluntarily tell me.
直到你主动告诉我。
Teacher, you are saying...
老师您是说...
If I keep it a secret from you...
如果我对你保密的话...
Why don't you ask?
你为什么不问？
Didn't I?
我没有吗？
Huaxian's problem...
华贤的问题...
Feast killer...
过节杀手...
And between you and Wu Shuomo.
还有你和吴硕墨之间。
They keep saying no one will understand...
他们一直说没有人会理解...
Hostility between you and Hua Qian .
你和花千骨之间的敌意 。
If I intervene you will think I am biased.
如果我介入， 你会认为我有偏见。
So I do whatever you want.
所以我就做你想做的事。
But yao...
但瑶...
How long do you want to do this...?
你想这样做多久……？
Pretending to be stupid and blind?
假装愚蠢和盲目？
You said it at the beginning...
你一开始就说过了...
You are trying to delete a family member's name.
您正在尝试删除家庭成员的姓名。
But what about now?
但现在呢？
What do you actually do?
你实际上是做什么的？
Jong Ye-ran.
钟艺兰.
I don't understand myself.
我自己都不明白。
Recently I had this thought.
最近 我有这样的想法。
If only you let the snake eat the parrot.
如果你让蛇吃掉鹦鹉就好了。
Yao.
姚。
I just want to tell you...
我只是想告诉你...
There are only two of us in this house ...
这房子里只有我们两个人 ...
And it will remain the same in the future.
未来也将保持不变。
I say this with all my heart.
我是 真心实意地说这句话的。
So you don't have to go far to get help.
因此，您无需走很远即可获得帮助。
I was wrong.
我错了。
No one is perfect. Humans make mistakes.
没有人是完美的。 人类会犯错误。
I made a mistake too...
我也犯了一个错误...
This is because of misunderstanding and prejudice.
这是因为误解和偏见。
I know you're stubborn...
我知道你很固执...
But you don't have to face it...
但你不必面对...
You are alone with your problems.
你独自面对你的问题。
As long as you need me...
只要你需要我...
i am here for you
我在这里等你
It's not too late to turn back.
现在回头还不算太晚。
What is that?
那是什么？
Miss... Ms. Fah left in a hurry...
小姐……发女士匆匆离开……
And I left this old friend.
然后我离开了这位老朋友。
Look, I brought you here.
瞧，我带你来这里的。
You don't know how to use your hand...
你不知道如何使用你的手...
Was it damaged because of the owner?
是因为主人的原因造成的吗？
You tried to make him sad...
你试图让他伤心...
By bringing guqin here?
把古琴带到这里来？
Cik Qianzhi, tunggu sekejap.
Cik Qianzhi, tunggu sekejap.
What else do you want?
你还想要什么？
This fix is famous and valuable.
这个修复是著名 且有价值的。
If it's normal...
如果是正常的话...
I won't send it from here.
我不会从这里发送它。
priceless?
无价？
please give it to me
请给我
How much.
多少。
Is there any news about Muyao yet?
慕瑶现在有消息了吗？
Today is exactly the third day.
今天正好是第三天。
Maybe you haven't found the clue yet.
也许你还没有找到线索。
I didn't notice him.
我没有注意到他。
Who knows if he actually looked into it?
谁知道他是否真的调查过呢？
That person is still locked up...
那人还被关着……
So maybe Mu Yao won’t sit still.
所以说不定慕瑶也 不会坐以待毙。
He is too slow.
他太慢了。
Do you think I should send it...
你觉得我应该发给你吗...
Wu Shuomo's limbs gave him...
吴硕莫的四肢 给了他……
How to speed up the investigation?
如何加快调查速度？
but...
但...
Lady, Whoamade has arrived.
女士，哇玛德来了。
Didn't you go to the store today?
你今天没去商店吗？
Mr. Qian, do you want to eat fish today?
钱先生，今天想吃鱼吗？
fish?
鱼？
My dad saw it yesterday...
我爸昨天看到了...
The fish in the lake look big and fat.
湖里的鱼看起来又大又肥。
You didn't do anything today.
你今天什么也没做。
What does it mean to go fishing with dad ?
和爸爸一起去钓鱼意味着什么 ？
Chefs don't buy fish?
厨师不买鱼？
This is different.
这是不同的。
Not all fish that the chef buys are the same.
厨师买的鱼并不都是一样的。
With the fish we catch.
和我们捕获的鱼一起。
You'll know the difference...
你就会知道其中的区别...
When I eat tonight
今晚吃饭的时候
- Do you want to go with dad? - Decent.
- 你想和爸爸一起去吗？ - 体面的。
Not a single fish ate the bait.
没有一条鱼 吃掉鱼饵。
The key to fishing is patience .
钓鱼的关键是耐心 。
You need to calm down.
你需要冷静下来。
Surprised fish...
惊讶的鱼...
When you're busy moving the stick.
当你忙着移动棍子时。
It is impossible to catch fish.
想要钓到鱼是不可能的。
I couldn't catch my dad either.
我也抓不到我爸爸。
It takes time.
这需要时间。
It's moving.
它在动。
There is one!
有一个！
see?
看？
Dad says he can't catch it, but he can.
爸爸 说他抓不到，但他可以。
Grab this. see?
抓住这个。 看？
This fish looks very fluffy.
这条鱼看起来非常毛茸茸的。
Kian.
基安.
If the bait is fat and fluffy...
如果鱼饵又肥又蓬松...
No fish can resist it.
没有鱼能抗拒它。
Come this way.
这边过来。
Here it is.
这里是。
Youth is synonymous with impatience .
青春就是急躁的代名词 。
You just need to practice a little more.
你只需要多练习一点。
Thanks for the advice, father.
谢谢你的建议，父亲。
Mom, I have no appetite...
妈妈，我没有胃口……
So he is getting thinner and thinner.
所以他越来越瘦。
Visit that person more often.
更频繁地拜访那个人。
When you have time.
当你有时间。
later.
之后。
I've been so busy lately...
我最近太忙了...
Until it becomes difficult to control your emotions.
直到变得难以控制自己的情绪。
Is it possible to meet my mother like this...
难道就这样能见到妈妈吗……
It will make him sadder.
这会让他更加难过。
are you okay. It's up to you.
你还好吗。 由你决定。
Miss, I sent you some fish soup from the kitchen.
小姐，我从厨房给您送来了鱼汤。
Please wait a moment.
请稍候。
A girl who grew up in a rich and powerful family...
一个生长在权贵之家的女孩……
Always look at the bigger picture.
始终 着眼于大局。
No matter what my son does...
不管我儿子做什么...
She is the only daughter of Hua Family...
她是华家唯一的女儿……
And Mr. Jong's wife.
还有Jong先生的妻子。
Why did you come here?
你为什么来这里？
See the impact of your actions.
查看您的行为的影响。
You are a disgrace to our family.
你是我们家族的耻辱。
Now we only have you.
现在我们只有你了。
You don't want to live in Huangcheng.
你不想住在皇城。
great.
伟大的。
From now on...
今后...
I listen to your advice.
我听你的建议。
You said you wouldn't hurt me again ...
你说过不会再伤害我的 ...
And I almost believe you.
我几乎相信你了。
I want to believe...
我想相信...
You may not relate...
你可能没有联系...
For my family.
为我的家庭。
But what happened to Linglong...
可是 玲珑到底怎么了……
Please make me realize that I can't forgive you.
请让我明白我无法原谅你。
Many people have had difficulties...
很多人都遇到过困难...
In the hands of the Hua family...
在华家手中……
And it goes unnoticed.
而且它不被注意。
You are a member of the Hua Family.
你是华家的人。
It makes you indifferent and conceited.
它让你变得冷漠 和自负。
You can pretend not to know...
你可以假装不知道...
Because you don't see it, but I...
因为你看不到，但我...
Unable to.
无法。
Where is the fish soup?
鱼汤在哪里？
Bring it here.
把它带到这里来。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
I leave it to you.
我把它留给你。
Tick...
打钩...
Do you want to sell all your stores?
您想出售所有商店吗？
that...
那...
I heard it from my father...
我是从我父亲那里听来的...
He assigned you to work for my brother...
他指派你为我哥哥工作...
Because you're smart...
因为你很聪明...
And I can control my extravagant brother.
而且 我可以控制我奢侈的弟弟。
They told me to sell that store ...
他们告诉我卖掉那家商店 ......
For non-profit purposes...
出于非营利目的...
But converting that into money...
但把它换成钱...
preparing...
准备...
For the future.
为将来。
Just make it the best.
只要做到最好就可以了。
Yes ma'am. I'll handle it.
是的女士。 我会处理的。
I told the store manager...
我跟店长说...
That you would go there.
你会去那里。
Go now.
现在出发。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
Are you done?
你做完了吗？
Last month I sent guqin...
上个月我寄了古琴...
Chess pieces a few days ago...
前几天的棋子...
Now it's a chessboard.
现在它是一个棋盘。
Can't I send them all at once?
我不能一次全部发送吗？
I was careless when packaging...
包装的时候不小心...
I didn't notice everything at once.
我没有一下子注意到一切。
So I sent it to Hwa...
于是我就发给华...
When I see
当我看见
Miss sent someone to take her things .
小姐派人来拿她的东西 。
Because he left it there...
因为他把它留在那里了...
I mean, he doesn't want to.
我的意思是，他不想。
That's unfair.
这不公平。
It's Miss Hua's.
是华小姐的。
It must be returned to its owner.
它必须归还给它的主人。
Don't come here again.
不要再来这里了。
On behalf of Fahrenheit...
代表华氏...
Take my word for it. He doesn't want that.
相信我的话。他不想要这样。
Why don't you want it? I still have my brushes and ink.
你为什么不想要它？ 我还有画笔和墨水。
me...
我...
Didn't you say you were sending something...
你不是说要送东西吗...
if you see
如果你看到
Don't forget your brushes and ink.
不要忘记你的画笔和墨水。
How about bringing it with you sometime?
什么时候带上它怎么样？
me...
我...
Dengarsini, Nanfeng.
Dengarsini, Nanfeng.
Although Mr. Fahrenheit is no longer your master's wife...
虽然飞轮海先生已经不再是 你师父的妻子了……
You have absolutely no chance.
你绝对没有机会。
So don't look for an excuse to come here.
所以不要找借口来这里。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I said it was impossible...
我说不可能...
Miss Hua will be interested in you...
华小姐一定会对你感兴趣……
So call it a night.
所以就到此为止吧。
No, I am not interested in Miss Hua...
不，我对华小姐没兴趣……
While we were at the Bell Residence...
当我们在贝尔住宅时......
You always find an excuse...
你总能找到借口...
To come to our area.
来到我们地区。
Don't think I don't know your plans .
别以为我不知道你的计划 。
I thought we were both slaves...
我以为我们都是奴隶...
So I won't reveal you.
所以我不会透露你的。
But I never thought you would take that risk...
但我没想到你会冒这个险...
So I must warn you.
所以我必须警告你。
No, I...
不，我...
Don't reject it.
不要拒绝它。
No matter what happens, you work for Mr. Jong...
不管发生什么， 你都是为Jong先生工作......
And Cik Hua won't be yours .
而 Cik Hua 不会是你的 。
I never thought that was nonsense...
我 从来没想过这是废话...
About Miss Hua.
关于华小姐。
I know your true intentions.
我知道你的真实意图。
This has to do with Cik Hua's reputation...
这跟Cik Hua的名气有关……
So I won't say anything.
所以我什么也不说。
But don't fool me.
但别骗我。
This time I will take a chessboard.
这次我要拿棋盘。
Please watch the action from now on.
从现在开始请注意动作。
Don't come here again.
不要再来这里了。
Cik Qianzhi.
Cik Qianzhi.
How dare you touch me?
你怎么敢碰我？
Don't overdo it!
不要太过分了！
As I said before, I will not open my mouth about this issue.
正如我之前所说， 我不会开口谈论这个问题。
- Let go. - Mr. Chenz.
- 松手。 - 陈茨先生。
You are my favorite person.
你是我最喜欢的人。
here.
这里。
great. Miss missed one spot.
伟大的。 小姐错过了一个位置。
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
Chenz!
陈兹！
Does a vase make you angry?
花瓶 会让你生气吗？
Why are you with him?
你为什么和他在一起？
He was anxious all day.
他一整天都很焦虑。
I think you know why.
我想你知道为什么。
Tell me what I don't know.
告诉我我不知道的事情。
I see Nanfeng always coming...
我看到南风总是来……
Through the back door...
从后门进去...
Get to know Cari Qianzhi.
认识卡里千之。
Nanfeng? What does he want?
南风？ 他想要什么？
I think I'm sending something ...
我想我正在发送一些东西 ...
What you left.
你留下了什么。
It seems like there's nothing left...
好像什么都没有剩下了...
디Kediaman Zhong.
디 Kediaman Zhong.
What else...
还有什么...
While we stayed at Zhong Residence...
当我们住在忠公馆时...
Nanfeng selalu datang...
Nanfeng selalu datang...
To our area.
到我们地区。
Qianzhi jadi started...
千纸佳迪开始了……
Because Nanfeng came to look for him yesterday.
因为昨天南风来找他了。
Nanfeng seems to have other intentions.
南风似乎另有打算。
Qianzhi didn't say anything...
千智没有说话……
Tentang Rawatan Nanfeng.
Tentang Rawatan 南风。
I think this girl...
我觉得这个女孩...
Protect Zhong Yelan and my assistant.
保护钟夜兰 和我的助理。
Amazing couple.
很棒的一对。
They don't talk to each other much.
他们彼此不怎么说话。
Don't tell me I'm playing a role...
别告诉我我是在演一个角色...
To unite them?
为了团结他们？
But girl, that person...
但是姑娘，那个人……
No need to worry.
不用担心。
Qianzhi lived his life. I shouldn't get involved.
千之过着自己的生活。 我不应该参与其中。
After a few days of boredom...
经过几天的无聊...
There is finally some good news.
终于有一些好消息了。
But Nanfeng works under Mr. Zhong.
但南风 是在钟先生手下工作的。
Mr. Yinxing, I understand your concerns.
银星先生，我理解您的担忧。
But I know Qianzhi...
但我知道千智...
And girls like you can get married.
像你这样的女孩 可以结婚。
If you are sure of your will ...
如果你确定自己的意愿 ...
Whoever they are, I will support you.
不管他们是谁， 我都会支持你。
I won't stop you because of their status.
我不会因为他们的身份而阻止你。
Life is short.
生命短暂。
Your happiness is most important.
你的幸福最重要。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
I don't have much time. I'll have to ask him.
我没有太多时间。 我得问问他。
Are you looking for me?
你在找我吗？
You are a daydreamer.
你是个白日梦者。
You shouldn't do that.
你不应该这样做。
Why are you keeping it a secret from me ?
你为什么要对我保密 ？
what?
什么？
If I don't ask...
如果我不问的话...
Are you planning to tell me...
你打算告诉我吗...
About your relationship with Nanfeng?
你和南风的关系？
Nanfeng and I have nothing to do with each other!
我和南风 没有任何关系！
I must die.
我必须死。
He doesn't seem to be in love.
他似乎没有恋爱。
Hua Rongzhou, mari sini.
Hua Rongzhou, mari sini.
Go ahead and try it. If you want to scare someone, follow me.
继续尝试。 如果你想吓唬别人，就跟我来。
Hello, Ms. Hua.
华小姐，您好。
Lift your head.
抬起头。
I heard you came to Hwa Residence...
听说你来华公馆了...
Get to know Cari Qianzhi.
认识卡里千之。
Fahrenheit, I went to send it...
华氏度，我去发了……
Things you left behind.
你留下的东西。
yes?
是的？
I don't remember leaving anything behind.
我不记得留下任何东西。
It's a gift from you.
这是你的礼物。
How dare you, Nanfeng!
南风你怎么敢！
I remind you of an honest person.
我让你想起一个诚实的人。
I didn't know you would give that reason...
我不知道你会给出这个理由...
Meet my assistant secretly at Hua Residence.
到华府偷偷会见我的助理。
Mr. Hua, Mr. Qianzhi and I have never...
我和华先生、 谦智先生从来没有……
Not lying! You came to Hua Residence in public.
没有说谎！ 你当众来到华府。
You two should become friends!
你们两个应该成为朋友！
I sincerely love Teacher Qianzhi...
我真心爱千之老师……
But he doesn't know that.
但他不知道这一点。
So there is no way for us to become friends.
所以我们没有办法成为朋友。
This is the truth, girl.
这是事实，女孩。
Is that true?
真的吗？
Miss Qianzhi is Miss's personal assistant.
千智小姐 是小姐的私人助理。
If we were related...
如果我们有血缘关系的话……
We can't hide it from you.
我们无法向您隐瞒。
This is just my hope.
这只是我的希望。
Cik Qianzhi 카캅...
Cik Qianzhi 카캅...
He will never see me again.
他再也见不到我了。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
It's no joke.
这不是玩笑。
You are Mr. I work under Zhong.
你是先生。我在钟手下工作。
Miss Hua is sad because of that.
华小姐 为此伤心不已。
It was a good thing I came all the way here to see you.
很高兴我千里迢迢来到这里见到你。
How dare you do something stupid?
你怎么敢做蠢事？
me...
我...
Don't come here again.
不要再来这里了。
Kian...
基安...
These two idiots.
这两个白痴。
If Qianzhi doesn't have feelings for you ...
如果千之对你没有感情的话 ……
Why didn't he tell me about your visit ?
他为什么不告诉我你来访的事 ？
But meeting in person?
但亲自见面？
Teacher Qianzhi gets angry at me every time he sees me.
千之老师每次看到我就生我的气。
He said I really asked to meet him...
他说我真的很想见他...
So he had no choice but to come to see me.
所以他没有办法，只能来见我。
If that person is really mad at you...
如果那个人真的 生你的气...
Why doesn't that person send someone...
那人怎么不派人来……
To kick you out?
要把你赶出去？
Why does he still come out to see you?
他怎么还出来见你？
Tick...
打钩...
Just forget it.
把它忘了吧。
I won't go on for too long...
我不会继续太久...
because of you...
因为有你...
Take my brother to Hua Residence.
带我哥去华府。
I am in your debt.
我欠你的情。
So I will pay you back right now .
所以我现在就还给你 。
You mean to give Miss Qianzhi to me ...
你的意思是要把千之小姐送给我 ……
As a reward?
作为奖励？
I have never thought of Qianzhi as a maid...
我从来没有想过把千纸当侍女……
So the word "compensation" is not appropriate.
所以“补偿”这个词并不恰当。
I won't stop you.
我不会阻止你。
That's all I can do.
这就是我能做的。
Do it accordingly.
相应地做。
Thank you, ma’am.
谢谢你，女士。
Before I go, I would like to ask one question.
走之前，我想问一个问题。
If I had to choose...
如果我必须选择的话...
Between your master and Qianzhi...
你师父和千纸之间……
Who will you choose?
你会选择谁？
Why do you ask that?
你为什么这么问？
Qianzhi is with me...
千智在我身边...
More than 10 years.
10多年了。
I don't want to see him suffer.
我不想看到他受苦。
As you know...
如你所知...
Your master and I are having a conflict.
我和你师父有矛盾。
If you have to choose between the two...
如果你必须在两者之间做出选择...
When the time comes...
在时机成熟时...
What are you going to do?
你会怎样做？
Just get this done.
只要把这件事做好就可以了。
Qianzhi finds it difficult to break up...
千植觉得分手很难……
So I will make the decision for him.
所以我会替他做决定。
Mr. Hua, excuse me...
华先生，对不起……
Because I can't choose.
因为我无法选择。
why?
为什么？
I am Mr. I work under Zhong.
我是先生 我在钟手下工作。
I have served him since I was a child.
我 从小就侍奉他。
So I understand his actions.
所以我理解他的行为。
He won't let me sacrifice my family...
他不会让我牺牲我的家人...
To protect him.
为了保护他。
Teacher Qianzhi is the only person I love.
千之老师是我唯一爱的人。
I know he is a soft-hearted person.
我知道他是一个心肠软的人。
She's the only woman I want to live with...
她是我唯一想一起生活的女人
But I cannot betray my master for his sake.
但我 不能为了主人而背叛他。
People who lack loyalty and sincerity...
缺乏忠诚和真诚的人...
can not believe it
不敢相信
I didn't think you were that smart.
我没想到你这么聪明。
All my words are sincere and come from my heart.
我所有的话 都是真诚的，都是发自内心的。
great. Between married couples...
伟大的。 夫妻之间...
At least one person must be smart.
至少 有一个人必须是聪明的。
Remember this.
记住这一点。
Do not take back your words.
不要收回你的话。
what?
什么？
Remember your words.
记住你的话。
If you change your mind...
如果你改变主意...
I am the first person to look for you.
我是第一个来找你的人。
Don't expect any help from me.
不要指望从我这里得到任何帮助。
Between you and Qianzhi...
你和千之之间……
It's all up to you.
全取决于你。
Thank you, Teacher Hua.
谢谢华老师。
Qianzhi pemalu.
Qianzhi pemalu.
Don't tell anyone what you heard today.
不要告诉任何人你今天听到的事情。
I will definitely keep my mouth shut.
我绝对会闭嘴。
We rarely go out.
我们很少出去。
Now that the reeds are out, let's prepare a wedding gift.
现在芦苇已经出来了， 我们来准备结婚礼物吧。
- Qianzhi yuntuk? - yes.
- 千智云图？ - 是的。
The stupid boy only thought about one thing.
傻孩子 只想到一件事。
Even if you're old...
就算你老了...
He doesn't know how to save money.
他不知道如何省钱。
I think I'll show off today .
我想我今天要炫耀一下 。
Luckily, Huang hasn't sold all of his stores yet.
幸运的是，黄还没有卖掉他所有的店铺。
Qianzhi would later become a civilian.
千之后来成为一名平民。
Because the location of the store is bad...
因为店的位置不好..
Too noticeable.
太引人注目了。
But with Qianzhi's cleverness...
但以千之的聪明……
If it's just a regular store...
如果只是普通的店...
I'm worried that he doesn't know how to manage it.
我担心他不知道如何处理。
He might close the door...
他可能会关门...
And loss. What will he do?
和损失。 他会做什么？
What are you...
你是做什么的...
- It's okay... - He's dirty.
- 没关系... - 他很脏。
Where did you get this choice of love?
你从哪里得到这种爱的选择？
Come this way.
这边过来。
I have a bruise on my knee. Does that hurt?
我的膝盖上有一块瘀伤。 疼吗？
Would you like me to take you to see a doctor?
要我带你去看医生吗？
Let me go!
让我走！
Please set him free.
请释放他。
Just forget it. let's go.
把它忘了吧。 我们走吧。
Take this. Don't play around too much.
拿着它。 不要玩太多。
look at me
看着我
I don't know why I sympathize with this...
我不知道为什么我会同情这个…
With those who suffer.
与那些受苦的人。
The little beggar's knees were bleeding.
小乞丐的膝盖在流血。
That person is so small...
那人好小啊……
But he didn't cry or make a fuss.
但他没有哭，也没有大惊小怪。
I wonder if he doesn't know...
我想知道他是否不知道...
Or are you not afraid of pain?
还是你不怕痛？
That person is just pretending to be sad...
那个人 只是假装悲伤而已……
When you fail to steal.
当你偷窃失败时。
The lady must not give him money.
女士一定不能给他钱。
No one will be fooled...
没有人会被愚弄...
As for the tricks used...
至于使用的技巧...
By street beggars.
被街头乞丐所为。
What do you mean by pretending to be sad?
假装悲伤是什么意思？
His knees were bleeding.
他的膝盖在流血。
Eventually, we all go through…
最终，我们都会经历……
difficult times.
困难时期。
I am not short of money.
我不缺钱。
I consider this...
我认为这...
To get good karma for myself .
为自己积善缘 。
Miss is easily fooled.
小姐很容易被骗。
I notice that your temper is getting worse.
我 发现你的脾气越来越坏了。
Yes, I confess.
是的，我承认。
I don't pay much attention to you...
我不太关注你...
But I try to fix it.
但我尝试修复它。
Do you think Qianzhi will be angry with me?
你觉得千之会生我的气吗？
Dia Menolak Nanfeng.
迪亚·梅诺拉克·南风.
He must be a miserable person...
他一定是一个很不幸的人……
And I didn't even notice.
我什至没有注意到。
How about now?
现在怎么样？
The lady is really careless.
夫人真是不小心啊。
I criticize myself because I put myself down.
我 批评自己，因为我贬低了自己。
That doesn't mean you can blame me.
这并不意味着你可以责怪我。
I still think about when you first met me...
我仍然会想起你第一次见到我的时候...
During ancestral rites?
祭祖的时候？
When I asked him if he remembered...
当我问他是否记得时...
He asked my name four times .
他问了我四次名字 。
Now it seems like you don't really remember.
现在看来你真的不记得了。
Please give me a hint.
请给我一个提示。
This is where you asked for my name...
这是你问我名字的地方...
For the first time
首次
so.
所以。
If you don't remember, just say it.
如果你不记得了，就说出来吧。
It's okay if you don't remember.
如果你不记得也没关系。
I can tell you a story.
我可以给你讲一个故事。
Aren't you curious why I know?
你难道不好奇我为什么知道吗？
What do beggars do?
乞丐做什么？
Because I was originally a beggar...
因为我本来就是个乞丐……
in the street.
在街上。
I almost hit your cart.
我差点撞到你的购物车了。
Come this way. Beat him.
这边过来。 打他。
What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
Longzhou!
龙州！
Is your last name Zhou?
你姓周吗？
Then I got a job at a tea shop...
后来 我在一家茶馆找到了一份工作...
And then I met you again.
然后我又遇见了你。
The lady came to the tea shop..
这位女士来到茶馆..
I'm going to find Master Hwayoung.
我要去寻找华阳大师。
They are two ordinary people.
他们是两个普通人。
I am overconfident in my abilities.
我 对自己的能力过于自信。
And I'd like to help you...
我想帮助你...
But in the end I was beaten.
但最后我还是被打败了。
At that time, the teacher said...
当时老师说...
If you want to protect someone...
如果你想保护一个人...
First I have to learn how to protect myself.
首先我必须学会如何保护自己。
What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
- Longzhou - Zhou Yong?
——龙州 ——周勇？
When we met for the third time...
当我们第三次见面时...
At ancestor worship ceremonies.
在祭祖仪式上。
This time I protected you...
这次是 我保护了你……
And myself.
还有我自己。
Please tap my shoulder...
请轻拍我的肩膀...
And tell me my future is bright.
并告诉我我的未来是光明的。
Your future is bright.
你的未来是光明的。
- What is your name? - what...
- 你叫什么名字？ - 什么...
- shit! I may have missed it. - Longzhou.
- 妈的！我可能错过了。 - 龙州。
fourth...
第四...
When I was transferred to look after Ms.'s area.
当我被调去照顾女士的区域时。
I was so confused that I couldn't hear.
我当时很困惑，听不清。
What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
My Name...
我的名字...
Huarongzhou.
华容洲。
After working at Zhong Residence for half a year...
在忠公馆 工作了半年之后……
I can finally walk next to you...
我终于可以走在你身边了
And he stood in front of his wife.
而他就站在了他妻子的面前。
Beggar, helper...
乞丐、帮手……
You?
你？
I told you I have a bad memory, right?
我 告诉过你我记性不好，对吗？
It's not that I have a bad memory.
并不是我记性不好。
Because I stutter...
因为我结巴了...
And you can't say your name clearly .
而且你也不能说清楚你的名字 。
Now looking back on the past...
现在 回想过去...
Can you ever forget that incident again ?
你还能忘记那件事吗 ？
Usually you don't talk much.
通常你话不多。
Why are you talking so much today?
今天怎么讲这么多？
The woman who told me...
那个女人告诉我...
tell me everything
告诉我一切
obey.
遵守。
Ier's Refuge
伊尔避难所
What did you tell them to sit down?
你叫他们坐下做什么？
My uncle still thinks it's too dangerous.
我叔叔仍然 认为这太危险了。
After this...
在这之后...
Uncle, if we don't take the risk...
叔叔， 如果我们不冒险的话...
We won't get anything.
我们不会得到任何东西。
Betul, Tapi, Ifey...
桦木、塔皮、伊菲……
Master has arrived!
师父来了！
hello.
你好。
You are here too, Mr. what?
先生，你也在这里。什么？
of.
的。
My brother hopes so...
哥哥希望如此...
Bring the goods to Yifei from the south...
把货物从南方带到一飞……
So I sent it here.
所以我把它发送到这里。
Mom and sister...
妈妈和姐姐...
I returned home a few days ago.
我几天前回国了。
They feel tired and in a bad mood.
他们感到疲倦且心情不好。
You think it's a hassle to bring things to me...
你觉得送东西给我很麻烦...
So they left the job to their aunt.
于是，他们 就把这份工作交给了姑妈。
good. I'm worried...
好的。 我很担心...
Mengmaid has been away all year...
萌娘已经离开了一整年了……
It will make you and the person uncomfortable.
这会让你和对方感到 不舒服。
Now I see you're still close...
现在我 发现你仍然很接近...
And Meng Maid really misses her family...
而萌娘 真的很想念她的家人……
I feel relieved.
我感到轻松多了。
Sir, my brother has been gone all year...
先生，我哥哥 已经离开一整年了……
And he can't take care of his family.
而且他无法照顾他的家人。
If we have time, we will do our best to help you.
如果我们有时间，我们会尽力帮助您。
Aide Meng is really...
孟助理真是……
It is the backbone of the Zhong Family business.
是钟家生意的支柱。
Doing business in the South...
在南方做生意...
Rely on it.
依靠它。
Thank you for your concern.
谢谢你的关心。
He is fortunate to serve.
他有幸能够服役。
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
How much.
多少。
take it.
拿去。
I have a store approval letter...
我有商店批准信...
With my name in it.
里面有我的名字。
I chose carefully this afternoon .
今天下午我是慎重选择的 。
Although the location is not right...
虽然位置不对...
We have a network of loyal customers.
我们拥有忠实的客户网络。
After all, the shops in this bustling area...
毕竟 这繁华地段的商店……
It is managed by a senior person.
它由一位资深人士管理。
You may not be able to run a store.
您可能无法经营商店。
If you're there, you can do it without me.
如果你在的话，不用我也能做到。
Inside is a set of jewels .
里面是一套珠宝 。
I've never used it before...
我以前从未使用过它...
So it looks like new.
所以看起来就像新的一样。
Your contract is in it too.
你的合同也在里面。
This is a token of my gratitude.
这是我的谢意。
Lady, if I did something wrong...
女士，如果我做错了什么……
Please punish me.
请惩罚我。
I have no objection.
我没有异议。
Don't kick me out, girl.
别把我赶出去，女孩。
- wake up. - ma'am
- 醒来。 - 女士
I'm not kicking you out.
我不会把你赶出去。
This is a wedding gift given to Nanfeng when he marries her.
这是南风娶她时送给她的结婚礼物。
Girl, I don't want to leave you.
姑娘，我不想离开你。
Saya dan Nanfeng cuma...
Saya dan Nanfeng cuma...
I may have to leave Hwangcheong soon.
我可能很快就要离开黄清了。
Luckily, I get it now.
幸运的是，我现在明白了。
If not, I'll take you...
没有的话 我就带你...
And it destroys your happiness.
它会破坏你的幸福。
Wherever you go...
不管你去哪...
I will go with you.
我和你一起去。
don't worry.
不用担心。
Jika Nanfeng buli wake nanti...
Jika Nanfeng buli wake nanti...
Even though it's not in Hwangcheong...
虽然不在黄清...
I will come back to protect you .
我会回来保护你的 。
No, I'll go with you.
不，我和你一起去。
Why do you want to come with me?
你为什么要跟我一起去？
This marriage involves your whole life.
这段婚姻 涉及你的一生。
Nan Feng is a good person...
南风是个好人……
And you love each other.
你们彼此相爱。
You don't have to worry about me.
你不用担心我。
After all, I can't afford to hire you forever.
毕竟，我 不可能永远雇用你。
So don't think about relying on me.
所以你别想着依赖我。
When did you start having feelings for Nanfeng?
你什么时候 开始对南风产生感情的？
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不告诉我？
Are you afraid that I will bother you?
你是怕我打扰你吗？
I just found out how he was feeling a few days ago.
我前几天才知道他的感受。
All this time I thought he liked you.
一直以来我都 以为他喜欢你。
I didn't tell you...
我没告诉你...
Because I think it's impossible between us.
因为我觉得我们之间是不可能的。
impossible?
不可能的？
I am now open minded...
我现在心态开放了...
And those are two different things.
这是两件不同的事情。
Conflict between Jong Ye-ran and me...
我和钟艺兰之间的矛盾……
There is no need to involve anyone else.
没有必要让其他人参与进来。
Miss said she wanted to leave Huangcheng .
小姐说她要离开皇城 。
Where do you want to go?
你想去哪里？
Who knows?
谁知道？
Anyway, I don't want to get stuck here.
无论如何， 我不想被困在这里。
The world is wide.
世界很广阔。
I need to go out and expand my experience.
我需要出去 拓展我的经验。
right?
正确的？
We postpone until the time comes.
我们 推迟到时机到来。
When you find someone you like ...
当你找到一个你喜欢的人时 ...
Please tell me right away.
请马上告诉我。
It doesn't matter who that person is.
那个人是谁并不重要。
If he is the man you want to marry...
如果他是你想嫁的男人...
I will marry you in style.
我 会优雅地嫁给你。
Selagi cik di Huangcheng...
Selagi cik di Huangcheng...
I'll be with you.
我会和你在一起。
Should we go quickly?
我们应该快点走吗？
- to let go! - Decent.
- 放手！ - 体面的。
Go get some wedding gifts...
去买点结婚礼物吧...
Help prepare food.
帮助准备食物。
I want to go to Bell Park.
我想去贝尔公园。
Want to go to Taman Zhong?
想去钟花园？
great. For your happiness...
伟大的。 为了你的幸福...
I can't wait any longer.
我不能再等了。
We need to solve this problem quickly .
我们需要尽快解决这个问题 。
Lakaman Bonus
拉卡曼奖金
Is Hwang your real name?
黄某是你的真名吗？
No, Tuan Muda Hua gave me that name.
不，是团慕达华 给我起这个名字的。
So what is your real name?
那么你的真名是什么？
Huang Aotian.
黄傲天。
Why did you change your name to Hwang?
为什么改姓黄？
Young Master Hua said.
华公子说道。
I think my name is so noble.
我觉得我的名字是如此高贵。
As if I were the owner and not him.
就好像我是主人而不是他一样 。
So I changed my name...
所以我改了名字...
With a name that is easy to remember.
具有易于记住的名称。
That seems like something he would do.
这 似乎是他会做的事情。